# **Network Engineer**

# **Network Engineer - Fordham University**

Santa Clara, CA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/ef287b8a93935226

Hard working technician with experience in problem resolution, team leadership, and customer service with a self-motivated goal of efficiency. Experience leading projects involving building, maintaining, and dismantling large scale active networks. Recognized for remaining charismatic and calm while returning high quality solutions in stressful situations. An entrepreneurial spirit of innovation and a passion for problem solving.

An attitude to strive for perfection and a genuine interest in customer satisfaction.

Willing to relocate to: San Mateo, CA

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# **Network Engineer**

Fordham University - Bronx, NY - May 2016 to Present

Recruited as a network engineer responsible for enacting the full life cycle of networking and server solutions including network maintenance and VIP client solutions. Challenged with the responsibility of training new hires and delegation of work.

- Created and maintained complex databases of current network status including new installs and issue resolution.
- Experience with hands on management and delegation of tasks on large scale projects.
- Configured and installed several switches, routers, hubs, and access points to expand network capabilities.
- Resolved large scale network connectivity issues.
- Trained 10+ new staff on network upkeep.
- Responsible for tracking IP usage in a large static environment.
- Designed network layouts for several buildings and offices.
- Troubleshot thousands of network related issues.
- Performed several network analysis tests and data captures using programs such as WireShark.
- Provided on-site support for network connectivity issues in time sensitive situations.

#### **Network Technician**

Highstreet IT / Fordham - Bronx, NY - May 2015 to August 2015

Summary: Recruited as a systems monitor to troubleshoot and resolve issues with malfunctioning systems. Involved in the decommission process of older systems.

- Responsible for monitoring the current state of all devices connected to our network.
- Completed Installation of new systems into server racks and configured them to be monitored by remote tools such as WUG and Solar winds.
- Responsible for troubleshooting malfunctioning systems.
- Created of several SQL programs and macro intensive excel files to make the systems easier to monitor.

# Infrastructure Technician

Highstreet IT / Fordham - Islandia, NY - May 2014 to August 2014

Summary: Recruited to wire the store fronts of 1000+ Sleepy's locations up and down the U.S east coast between Maine and South Carolina. Responsible for setting up new locations and troubleshooting issues

in existing locations.

(914) 843-9169

WellsAustyn@gmail.com

- Installed and configured POD and POS equipment in hundreds of storefronts.
- Responsible for creating cable connections to each POS.
- Configured and installed remote switches and routers for each location.
- Averaged 2-3 store setups per day.

## **Electronic Repair Technician**

Highstreet IT / Fordham - Islandia, NY - May 2013 to August 2013

Summary: Recruited to aid warehouse functions in the department of refurbished equipment. Challenged to refurbish all malfunctioning equipment back to working standards.

- Responsible for repair of all malfunctioning Pc's, phones, printers, and servers.
- Installed new software updates.
- Cleaned and reimaged virus infected Pc.
- Upgraded Pc hardware.
- Assisted in warehouse management of hardware inventory for maintenance support.

## **Network Security Internship**

Fordham University - Bronx, NY - March 2012 to May 2012

Summary: Interned under the head of IT Security at Fordham University. Responsible for all data collection and management.

- Performed intrusion testing.
- Responsible for password basic password checks and resets.
- Created several large macro intensive excel files.

## **EDUCATION**

#### **Bachelor of Arts in Computer Science in Computer Science**

University at Albany (SUNY)

September 2012 to May 2016

#### **SKILLS**

C+ (2 years), Cabling (1 year), Command Line Interface (1 year), maintenance (1 year), network analysis (1 year), Microsoft Excel (4 years), Putty (1 year), WireShark (1 year)

## ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

#### Relevant Skills:

- Proficient in: Microsoft Power Point, Microsoft Excel, Command Line Interface, and C++
- Experience in: Office management, Cabling, Switch / Rack Installations, Network maintenance, troubleshooting equipment, and Network Analysis.